Institute for First Amendment Studies Records MS074
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Institute for First Amendment Studies Records
1984 -- 1988
1920 -- 1999
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
The Institute for First Amendment Studies
MS074
44.75 Linear Feet
429 Audiovisual Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized in six series: Institute for First Amendment Studies publications; Subject files; Audiocassettes; Videocassettes; Periodicals; Tax records.
Scope and Contents
The Institute for First Amendment Studies (IFAS) records consist of correspondence, clippings, direct mailings received from conservative Christian organizations and groups opposing the Christian right, publications, tax forms, and other papers pertaining to organizations, people, and ideas associated with conservative Christian groups or their opposition. In addition, the collection contains audio cassettes, videocassettes, and periodicals from and about Christian groups covering similar topics. Most materials were produced between 1984 and 1998. Topics covered include political action, abortion, censorship, education, and Supreme Court decisions. Groups such as the Christian Coalition (particularly its Road to Victory conferences), Focus on the Family, Concerned Women of America, the American Family Association (formerly the National Federation for Decency), the Council for National Policy, Colorado for Family Values, National Association of Christian Educators/Citizens for Excellence in Education (NACE/CEE), and D. James Kennedy's Coral Ridge Church are well represented. Materials produced by the Institute for First Amendment Studies are also part of the collection, including the newsletters Freedom Writer and Walk Away. Freedom Writer began publication in 1984 under the title Control Q. It disseminated information on the activities of the Religious Right, particularly pertaining to the separation of church and state and freedom of the press. Walk Away, created in 1989, focused on religious fundamentalism from a religious rather than political perspective and provided support to those leaving a fundamentalist faith.
Biographical / Historical
The Institute for First Amendment Studies (IFAS) was founded in 1984 by Skipp Porteous and Barbara Simon in Great Barrington, Massachusetts, in order to counter the American Religious Right's involvement in politics. Porteous was ordained as a minister by the Harvest Fields Missionary and Evangelistic Association in 1968, and served in churches in California and New York. He transferred his ministerial credentials to the Elim Fellowship upon moving to New York. In 1977, following the dissolution of his first marriage, Porteous began questioning his faith. Porteous and Simon met and married in the late 1970s.
In 1984, Porteous and Simon became concerned about the influence wielded by conservative Christians in the local Republican Party, and as a result became involved in public forums involving the separation of church and state. In an effort to inform the public about the Religious Right and their activities, they formed the Institute for First Amendment Studies, which began publishing the newsletter Control Q, later renamed Freedom Writer, in September 1984. This newsletter disseminates information on the activities of the Religious Right, particularly as it pertains to the separation of church and state and other First Amendment issues such as freedom of the press.
IFAS began collecting information on the people and organizations that form the Religious Right, and providing this information to mass media outlets as well as through the Freedom Writer. IFAS research has been used by national television networks, several national newspapers and magazines, and wire services. With the formation of IFAS, Porteous also began appearing on radio and television shows, sometimes paired with conservative Christians such as Jerry Falwell. In 1989 IFAS began publishing Walk Away, a newsletter focused specifically on religious fundamentalism from a religious rather than political perspective. Walk Away also provides support to those who are leaving a fundamentalist faith. IFAS closed in 2001.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Content Warning
This finding aid contains language that may be offensive or outdated. Because such language is in titles or direct transcription of published materials, it has not been changed. Keeping this language intact provides the most accurate depiction of the creators' intent, and can potentially tell us important things about bigotry and bias on the part of the creators, or in a particular historical context. For more information on DCA's content warning policy please visit our website.
Institute for First Amendment Studies; Christianity and politics--United States--History--20th century.; Media and broadcast history
- Institute for First Amendment Studies publications, 1984 -- 1997; MS074.001; 0.55 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains issues of Freedom Writer and Walk Away, peridiocals published by the Institute for First Amendment Studies. Most issues of Freedom Writer from Sept. 1984 (the first issue) through Sept./Oct. 1997 are represented, as is much of Walk Away from Spring 1989 through Spring 1995. Copies of most of the missing issues of Freedom Writer can be found in the subject files, in box 46, folder 011.
  These publications are folder-level cataloged. The publications were received in chronological order, by publication title, and this order has been preserved. Freedom Writer, which was titled Control Q from vol. 1, no. 1 through Vol. 2, no. 2, reports on and analyzes the activities of the Religious Right in America, and discusses issues pertaining to religious freedom. Walk Away is published for former fundamentalists and addresses issues relating to leaving fundamentalist religious groups.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically, then chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - [Control Q (Freedom Writer), Sept. -Feb.; Freedom Writer, Mar.-Oct.], 1984 -- 1986; MS074.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - [Freedom Writer, Jan. - Nov/Dec.], 1987 -- 1991; MS074.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - [Freedom Writer, May/June -Dec.], 1992 -- 1994; MS074.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - [Freedom Writer, Jan. -Dec.], 1995; MS074.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - [Freedom Writer, Jan./Feb.-Sept./Oct.], 1996 -- 1997; MS074.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - [Walk Away], 1989 -- 1995; MS074.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
    Spring 1989-Spring 1995
- Subject files, 1920 -- 1999; 1985 -- 1996; MS074.002; 38.4 Linear Feet
  Subject files of newspaper and magazine clippings, correspondence, and newsletters produced by or about the American religious right and fundamentalist Christian groups, collected by the Institute for First Amendment Studies (IFAS). Most materials date from 1985 to 1996. These materials were collected as part of IFAS' efforts to document and counter the activities of the religious right. The subject files as a whole cover an extensive range of individuals, groups, and ideas that were part of the religious right or its opposition in the late 20th century, including the Christian Coalition, the National Association of Christian Educators/Citizens for Excellence in Education, Focus on the Family, D. James Kennedy and the Coral Ridge Church, the Council for National Policy, Colorado for Family Values, and the American Family Association, as well as humanistic organizations. This series originally included many clippings from major newspapers, including the New York Times, the Washington Post, USA Today and the Wall Street Journal, and major national magazines, which were removed during processing. The original order of the subject files has been maintained as far as possible. Most files were received in alphabetical order, the exceptions being larger collections on the American Family Association/Don Wildmon, the Christian Coalition and Pat Robertson, the Christian Coalition's 1996 Road to Victory campaign, Colorado for Family Values, the Council for National Policy, D. James Kennedy/Coral Ridge Church and the National Association for Christian Educators (NACE)/Citizens for Excellence in Education (CEE). These larger subject collections have not been interfiled into the larger alphabetical collection, but have been placed at the end of the subject files series. In addition, materials on Abortion and the Supreme Court were grouped within the alphabetical sequence of materials, but out of alphabetical order; they have been placed at the end of the A's and S's, respectively. A small group of files beginning with the letter "P" were received with materials relating to NACE/CEE and were left in that location during processing (i.e., they are filed out of alphabetical order, in box 66).
  This series is arranged alphabetically by subject/correspondent.
  - ABC (American Broadcasting Company), 1986; MS074.002.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - ABC Day Care, 1988 -- 1989; MS074.002.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Abrams, Sol, 1992; MS074.002.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Accelerated Christian Education, 1984 -- 1987; MS074.002.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Access (Australia), 1992; MS074.002.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Accuracy in Academia, 1986; MS074.002.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Accuracy in Media, 1993 -- 1995; MS074.002.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - ACE Investigations [part 1 of 2], 1996; MS074.002.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - ACE Investigations [part 2 of 2], 1996; MS074.002.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - ACLJ - American Center for Law-Justice, 1993; MS074.002.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - A.C.L.U., 1988 -- 1995; MS074.002.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Act Up, 1994; MS074.002.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Action Alert, 1995; MS074.002.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Action Council for Peace in the Balkans, 1994; MS074.002.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Action, Lancaster County, 1990 -- 1993; MS074.002.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - ACTION, Northampton County, MS074.002.001.00016 (Box 1)
    No Date Available
  - Activists, 1985 -- 1996; MS074.002.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - AD2000, 1987; MS074.002.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Paul I., 1995 -- 1996; MS074.002.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Adelle, Stan, 1995; MS074.002.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - ADL (Anti-defamation League) [part 1 of 3], 1990 -- 1996; MS074.002.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - ADL (Anti-defamation League) [part 2 of 3], 1993; MS074.002.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - ADL (Anti-defamation League) [part 3 of 3], 1993; MS074.002.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - Anti-Defamation League, Washington, DC, 1991 -- 1993; MS074.002.001.00024 (Box 1)
    6/11/93
  - Adler, Louise, 1990 -- 1993; MS074.002.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - Adoption, 1986 -- 1992; MS074.002.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - Adult bookstore mailing list, 1987; MS074.002.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - Adultery, 1990; MS074.002.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - Advocates for Life Ministries, 1995 -- 1996; MS074.002.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - Aesthetic Realism Foundation, 1994 -- 1995; MS074.002.001.00030 (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action, 1988 -- 1996; MS074.002.001.00031 (Box 1)
  - Africa, 1988 -- 1992; MS074.002.001.00032 (Box 1)
  - African-American Catholic Congregation, 1991; MS074.002.001.00033 (Box 1)
  - African American history, 1990 -- 1994; MS074.002.001.00034 (Box 1)
  - African Americans for Humanism, 1992; MS074.002.001.00035 (Box 1)
  - Against Censorship Together, 1989 -- 1990; MS074.002.001.00036 (Box 1)
  - Aggressive Christian Training Corps, 1989; MS074.002.001.00037 (Box 1)
  - Ahmanson, Howard, 1992; MS074.002.001.00038 (Box 1)
  - AID/Religion, 1988; MS074.002.001.00039 (Box 1)
  - AIDS, 1985 -- 1995; MS074.002.001.00040 (Box 1)
  - AIDS/Berkshire County, sex, education, 1994; MS074.002.001.00041 (Box 1)
  - AIDS education, 1994 -- 1996; MS074.002.001.00042 (Box 1)
  - Akerley, Ben Edward, 1993 -- 1994; MS074.002.001.00043 (Box 1)
  - Alabama, 1994 -- 1996; MS074.002.001.00044 (Box 1)
  - Alabama education laws, 1992; MS074.002.001.00045 (Box 1)
  - Alabama Family Institute, 1995; MS074.002.001.00046 (Box 1)
  - Alama, Tony, 1992 -- 1995; MS074.002.001.00047 (Box 1)
  - Alaska, 1995; MS074.002.001.00048 (Box 1)
  - Alcohol, 1984 -- 1994; MS074.002.001.00049 (Box 1)
  - Alcoholism groups, 1990 -- 1996; MS074.002.001.00050 (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Lamar, 1990 -- 1996; MS074.002.001.00051 (Box 1)
  - Alice's Restaurant metaphor, 1969; MS074.002.001.00052 (Box 1)
  - Aliens, 1991 -- 1992; MS074.002.001.00053 (Box 1)
  - Alive & Free, 1986; MS074.002.001.00054 (Box 1)
  - Allen, Ethan, 1990; MS074.002.001.00055 (Box 1)
  - Allen, George F. (Gov VA 1994-), 1993 -- 1996; MS074.002.001.00056 (Box 1)
  - Allen, William, 1989 -- 1992; MS074.002.001.00057 (Box 1)
  - Alliance Defense Fund, 1995; MS074.002.001.00058 (Box 1)
  - Alternatives, 1989 -- 1991; MS074.002.001.00059 (Box 1)
  - Altevogt, William, 1991 -- 1992; MS074.002.001.00060 (Box 1)
  - Amazing Grace, 1990; MS074.002.001.00061 (Box 1)
  - Amazing stories - religion, 1992; MS074.002.001.00062 (Box 1)
  - Ambassador Report, 1987 -- 1993; MS074.002.001.00063 (Box 1)
  - American Arts Alliance, 1990; MS074.002.001.00064 (Box 1)
  - America First Curriculum, 1994; MS074.002.001.00065 (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Women (AAUW), 1994; MS074.002.001.00066 (Box 1)
  - American Atheist Newsletters, 1986 -- 1992; MS074.002.001.00067 (Box 1)
  - American Bar Association, 1987 -- 1994; MS074.002.001.00068 (Box 1)
  - American Bikers, 1984 -- 1987; MS074.002.001.00069 (Box 1)
  - Amerikan Christian Party, 1994; MS074.002.001.00070 (Box 1)
  - American Coalition for Life Advocate, 1995 -- 1996; MS074.002.001.00071 (Box 1)
  - American Conference on Religious Movements, 1989; MS074.002.001.00072 (Box 1)
  - American Conservative Union, 1996; MS074.002.001.00073 (Box 1)
  - American Family Association [part 1 of 2], 1989 -- 1996; MS074.002.001.00074 (Box 1)
  - American Family Foundation [part 1 of 2], 1988 -- 1989; MS074.002.001.00075 (Box 1)
  - American Family Foundation [part 2 of 2], 1986 -- 1988; MS074.002.001.00076 (Box 1)
  - American Family Foundation, 1989 -- 1993; MS074.002.001.00077 (Box 1)
  - American Freedom Coalition, 1988 -- 1992; MS074.002.001.00078 (Box 1)
  - Amerikan Freedom Fighters, 1985; MS074.002.001.00079 (Box 1)
  - American Heritage Association, MS074.002.001.00080 (Box 1)
  - American Gay Lesbian Atheists, 1990 -- 1995; MS074.002.001.00081 (Box 1)
  - American Humanist Association, 1995; MS074.002.001.00082 (Box 1)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1988 -- 1994; MS074.002.001.00083 (Box 1)
  - American Bikers (2), 1983 -- 1987; MS074.002.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - American Booksellers (Foundation for Free Expression), 1990 -- 1993; MS074.002.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - American Coalition for Traditional Values, 1984 -- 1985; MS074.002.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - American Family Association [part 2 of 2], 1992 -- 1995; MS074.002.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - American Jewish Committee, Church/State Conference, 1990 -- 1992; MS074.002.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - American Jewish Committee Publication, 1990 -- 1992; MS074.002.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - American Jewish Congress (Fund for Religious Liberty), 1985 -- 1995; MS074.002.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - American Life League, Inc., 1986 -- 1995; MS074.002.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - American Nation Film Co. Inc., 1992 -- 1994; MS074.002.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - American Rationalist, 1991; MS074.002.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - American Renewal, 1995; MS074.002.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - American Rights Coalition, MS074.002.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - American Spectator, MS074.002.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - Americanism Educational League, 1990; MS074.002.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - AFSI, Americans for a Safe Israel, 1994; MS074.002.002.00016 (Box 2)
  - Americans for Constitutional Freedom, 1986; MS074.002.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - America's Constitutional heritage (transcript), MS074.002.002.00018 (Box 2)
  - Americans for Religious Liberty [part 1 of 2], 1975 -- 1996; MS074.002.002.00019 (Box 2)
  - Americans for Religious Liberty [part 2 of 2], 1985 -- 1995; MS074.002.002.00020 (Box 2)
  - Americans for Religious Liberty [part 1 of 2], 1987 -- 1995; MS074.002.002.00021 (Box 2)
  - Americans for Religious Liberty [part 2 of 2], 1987 -- 1991; MS074.002.002.00022 (Box 2)
  - A T & T, 1995; MS074.002.002.00023 (Box 2)
  - Americans United for Life, 1992; MS074.002.002.00024 (Box 2)
  - Americans United for Separation of Church & State, press releases, 1984 -- 1994; MS074.002.002.00025 (Box 2)
  - Americans United for Separation of Church & State, publications [part 1 of 2], 1985 -- 1996; MS074.002.002.00026 (Box 2)
  - Americans United for Separation of Church & State, publications [part 2 of 2], 1987 -- 1993; MS074.002.002.00027 (Box 2)
  - Americans United for Separation of Church & State - general, 1986 -- 1994; MS074.002.002.00028 (Box 2)
  - Amnesty International, 1987 -- 1989; MS074.002.002.00029 (Box 2)
  - Anarchy, 1993; MS074.002.002.00030 (Box 2)
  - Ankerberg, John, 1987 -- 1993; MS074.002.002.00031 (Box 2)
  - Anti-gay organizations, 1990 -- 1995; MS074.002.002.00032 (Box 2)
  - Anti-racism, 1984 -- 1994; MS074.002.002.00033 (Box 2)
  - Antisemitism, 2 of 2, 1984 -- 1996; MS074.002.002.00035 (Box 2)
  - Antisemitism in the Berkshires, 1995; MS074.002.020.00001 (Box 20)
  - Antisemitism - Montana, 1995; MS074.002.020.00002 (Box 20)
  - Antisemitism project, 1985 -- 1994; MS074.002.020.00003 (Box 20)
  - Anti-Terrorism Bill, 1995; MS074.002.020.00004 (Box 20)
  - Apartheid in South Africa, 1984 -- 1985; MS074.002.020.00006 (Box 20)
  - Apologia Ministries, 1993; MS074.002.020.00007 (Box 20)
  - Areopagus II America, 1991; MS074.002.020.00008 (Box 20)
  - Arizona: Misc., 1985 -- 1996; MS074.002.020.00009 (Box 20)
  - Arizona Citizens Project, 1994 -- 1997; MS074.002.020.00010 (Box 20)
  - Arizona Proposition 110, 1992; MS074.002.020.00011 (Box 20)
  - Arkansas, 1991 -- 1994; MS074.002.020.00012 (Box 20)
  - Armageddon, 1984 -- 1991; MS074.002.020.00013 (Box 20)
  - Armey, Dick, 1995; MS074.002.020.00014 (Box 20)
  - Arms race, 1984 -- 1985; MS074.002.020.00015 (Box 20)
  - Armstrong, Bill, 1992; MS074.002.020.00016 (Box 20)
  - Arrington, Juanita Roby, People's Mouthpiece, 1992; MS074.002.020.00017 (Box 20)
  - Arts, 1990; MS074.002.020.00018 (Box 20)
  - Arts censorship project, ACLU, 1992 -- 1995; MS074.002.020.00019 (Box 20)
  - Aryan Nation, 1986 -- 1995; MS074.002.020.00020 (Box 20)
  - Assemblies of God, 1988 -- 1991; MS074.002.020.00021 (Box 20)
  - AG General Council, 1989 [1 of 2], 1987 -- 1989; MS074.002.020.00022 (Box 20)
    AG = Assemblies of God
  - AG General Council, 1989 [2 of 2], 1987 -- 1989; MS074.002.020.00023 (Box 20)
  - Atheism - misc., 1989 -- 1993; MS074.002.020.00024 (Box 20)
  - Atheism - Atheist Network Journal, 1991 -- 1995; MS074.002.020.00025 (Box 20)
  - Atheism - Northeast Atheist, 1992 -- 1993; MS074.002.020.00026 (Box 20)
  - Atheists United of S.F., 1991; MS074.002.020.00027 (Box 20)
  - Aware: Woman Center for Choice, 1995; MS074.002.020.00028 (Box 20)
  - Abortion [1 of 2], 1989 -- 1997; MS074.002.020.00029 (Box 20)
  - Abortion [2 of 2], 1985 -- 1994; MS074.002.020.00030 (Box 20)
  - [Anti-abortion material aimed at healthcare providers], MS074.002.020.00031 (Box 20)
  - Anti-abortion technology, 1995; MS074.002.020.00032 (Box 20)
  - Abortion, anti, 1991 -- 1996; MS074.002.020.00033 (Box 20)
  - Abortion, court rulings, legislation, 1985 -- 1995; MS074.002.020.00034 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - activists, 1994 -- 1995; MS074.002.020.00035 (Box 20)
  - Abortion/clinic violence assassins, 1991 -- 1996; MS074.002.020.00036 (Box 20)
  - Abortion pro-choice, 1984 -- 1994; MS074.002.020.00037 (Box 20)
  - Abortion clinic bombings, 1984 -- 1991; MS074.002.020.00038 (Box 20)
  - Abortion clinic bombings, winter 1984-1985, 1985 -- 1987; MS074.002.020.00039 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - clinic bombings 1995, 1984 -- 1996; MS074.002.020.00040 (Box 20)
  - Abortion clinic, 92-93 attacks, 1993 -- 1994; MS074.002.020.00041 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - Christian Coalition statements, 1995; MS074.002.020.00042 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - clinic projects, 1988 -- 1996; MS074.002.020.00043 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - right to life, 1989 -- 1994; MS074.002.020.00044 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - Catholic Church views, 1989 -- 1995; MS074.002.020.00045 (Box 20)
  - Abortion clinic protection, 1989 -- 1995; MS074.002.020.00046 (Box 20)
  - Abortion: Clinton, 1992 -- 1995; MS074.002.020.00047 (Box 20)
  - Abortion: phony clinics, 1991 -- 1994; MS074.002.020.00048 (Box 20)
  - Abortion / Bush years, 1989 -- 1992; MS074.002.020.00049 (Box 20)
  - Catholics - response lobbying abortion, 1984 -- 1993; MS074.002.020.00050 (Box 20)
  - Abortion consent law, 1987 -- 1992; MS074.002.020.00051 (Box 20)
  - Abortion counseling, 1985 -- 1995; MS074.002.020.00052 (Box 20)
  - Abortion distress, 1989 -- 1994; MS074.002.020.00053 (Box 20)
  - Abortion and fetal tissue research, 1989 -- 1994; MS074.002.020.00054 (Box 20)
  - Abortion foes - elected, 1987 -- 1992; MS074.002.020.00055 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - funding, 1989 -- 1995; MS074.002.020.00056 (Box 20)
  - Abortion / GOP, 1995 -- 1996; MS074.002.020.00057 (Box 20)
  - Abortion, anti's, photos, 1995; MS074.002.020.00058 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - hospitals, 1995; MS074.002.020.00059 (Box 20)
  - Abortion law (incl. Roe v. Wade), 1989 -- 1995; MS074.002.020.00060 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - MA - Brookline, 1995; MS074.002.020.00061 (Box 20)
  - Abortion / med profession, 1991; MS074.002.020.00062 (Box 20)
  - Abortions - military, 1990 -- 1993; MS074.002.020.00063 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - minors, 1995; MS074.002.020.00064 (Box 20)
  - NARAL - National Abortion Rights Action League, 1995; MS074.002.020.00065 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - parental consent, 1995; MS074.002.020.00066 (Box 20)
  - Abortion partial birth, 1995 -- 1996; MS074.002.020.00067 (Box 20)
  - Abortion picketing, 1995; MS074.002.020.00068 (Box 20)
  - Abortion pill, 1997; MS074.002.020.00069 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - protestors, 1991 -- 1995; MS074.002.020.00070 (Box 20)
  - ARM - Abortion Rights Mobilization suit, 1986 -- 1993; MS074.002.020.00071 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - post Webster 7/89, 1989 -- 1992; MS074.002.020.00072 (Box 20)
  - Abortion / pro-choice #2 [1 of 2], 1987 -- 1994; MS074.002.020.00073 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - pro-choice #2 [part 2 of 2], 1985 -- 1989; MS074.002.020.00074 (Box 20)
  - National Coalition of Abortion Providers / Fitzsimmons, MS074.002.020.00075 (Box 20)
  - Anti-abortion film - Hard Truth, 1992; MS074.002.020.00076 (Box 20)
  - Reagan & his administration's response to clinic bombings, 1987; MS074.002.020.00077 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - Reagan admin., 1985 -- 1987; MS074.002.020.00078 (Box 20)
  - Abortion / Reagan, 1984 -- 1988; MS074.002.020.00079 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - Republican, 1996; MS074.002.020.00080 (Box 20)
  - Abortion restrictions, 1996; MS074.002.020.00081 (Box 20)
  - California Republicans for Choice, 1992; MS074.002.020.00082 (Box 20)
  - Abortion rights, 1989 -- 1995; MS074.002.020.00083 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - RU486, 1990 -- 1996; MS074.002.020.00084 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - self-help, 1989; MS074.002.020.00085 (Box 20)
  - Abortion statistics, 1989 -- 1994; MS074.002.020.00086 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - various anti-abortion groups - small, 1993; MS074.002.020.00087 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - Alabama, 1993; MS074.002.020.00088 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - Arizona, 1988; MS074.002.020.00089 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - Arkansas, 1994; MS074.002.020.00090 (Box 20)
  - Abortion, California, 1989 -- 1995; MS074.002.020.00091 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - Canada, 1988 -- 1995; MS074.002.020.00092 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - Colorado, 1993; MS074.002.020.00093 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - Connecticut, 1985 -- 1996; MS074.002.020.00094 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - Delaware, 1993; MS074.002.020.00095 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - Florida, 1989 -- 1995; MS074.002.020.00096 (Box 20)
  - Abortion - Georgia, 1987 -- 1989; MS074.002.020.00097 (Box 20)
  - Abortion: Guam, 1990; MS074.002.020.00098 (Box 20)
  - Abortion / Idaho, 1990; MS074.002.020.00099 (Box 20)